It's Mount Fuji!
是富士山
It's so beautiful!
好美喔
It deserves to be called the No. 1 mountain in Japan.
真不愧是日本第一的高山
What is that?
那是什么啊
That's the newly constructed Nishitamashi Twin Towers.
那个是西多摩市新盖的双塔摩天大楼
The two towers are 319 meters and 294 meters tall,
标高分别为319米跟294米
which makes them the tallest buildings in Japan.
是日本第一高的双塔大楼
I really want to go there.
真想去看看耶
Professor,
博士
can we visit that place on the way back home from camping?
明天露营完回家的时侯顺便去看看吧
We might have to take a detour...
这样可能会绕点远路…
Fine, we can go.
也好  那就去吧
Nishitamashi City...
西多摩市…
Because I exposed the crimes committed by the former mayor,
因为我揭发了前市长的罪行
Teiji Moriya challenged me.
森谷帝二因此对我下了战书
By the way...
话说回来…
These guys really love camping.
这些家伙还真喜欢露营呢
We'll go camping tomorrow and the day after tomorrow, too...
明天去露营  后天也露营…
I'm so full!
我吃饱了
You haven't eaten up all the rice.
你的饭没吃干净耶
My mom told me that if you leave even a bit of rice behind,
我妈说如果留下任何一颗米粒
you'll be punished by god.
就会被老天爷惩罚的
That's right.
没错
The farmers worked hard
米是农民辛辛苦苦
and go through eighty-eight processes to produce the rice.
经过八十八道手续碾制的呢
Eighty-eight processes?
八十八道
If we disassemble the word 'rice',
把"米"字拆开来看
it becomes the number eighty-eight.
就成了"八十八"吧
Really?
是吗
It's true!
真的耶  真的耶
It really is!
真的耶
So, a person's 88th birthday is called 'Rice Birthday'.
所以过八十八岁生日就称为"米寿"
Just so you know,
另外顺便告诉你们好了
one's 77th birthday is called 'Joyous Birthday'.
七十七岁称作"喜寿"
And 99th birthday is called 'White Birthday'.
而九十九岁生日叫作"白寿"
Do you know why the 77th birthday is called 'Joyous Birthday'?
知道为什么"喜寿"是七十七岁吗
That's because the word 'Joyous' in cursive style
那是因为"喜寿"的"喜"字的草书体
looks just like the number seventy-seven, right?
看起来就像七十七的关系  对吧
The word 'hundred' will become the word 'white' if the upper line is removed.
而白寿是指百字去一就变成了白字
I always felt that
从以前开始我就一直觉得
the two of you knew too much.
你们两个知道的还真多
Are you guys lying about your age?
你们两个不会是谎报年龄吧
Ha... he's right about that.
哈…被他说中了
Right, I'll give you guys a riddle.
好  我出个谜题给你们猜猜看
What is one's 44th birthday called?
四十四岁生日该怎么称呼呢
Fourty-four...
四十四岁…吗
The answer is a kanji and three katakanas.
提示是这是由一个汉字和三个片假名组成
You could ignore the word 'birthday'.
寿字可以忽略
A kanji and three katakanas.
由一个汉字和三个片假名
What would it be?
到底是什么啊
Fourty-four... Eighty-eight... it can't be.
四十四…八十八…不会吧
Professor, I got the answer, but it's so boring.
博士  虽然我猜到了  可是这超无聊的哦
Really? What about Ai?
是吗  那小哀知道了吗
I don't know either!
我也猜不出来
Me neither!
我也是
All right, time to reveal the answer.
好  答案揭晓
Fourty-four is half of eighty-eight, right?
四十四刚好是八十八的一半  对吧
Eighty-eight is 'rice'
八十八是米
in English,
而米的英文是RICE
and the word 'half' is (HAN) is Japanese,
因为是一半 [HAN]
so it's half bowl of rice (HAN RICE).
所以就是半碗饭[HAN RICE]咯
Ha... I knew it...
哈…果然…
What's wrong?
怎么啦
If I serve half a bowl of rice three times (SAN),
半碗饭添个三次 [SAN]
it becomes (SUNRISE).
就变成日出 [SUNRISE]
I'm just joking.
开玩笑的啦
I peed a little on my pants.
尿了一点在裤子上…
It's so cold.
好冷
We might go to the Nishitamashi twin towers tomorrow.
明天可能会到西多摩市的双塔摩天大楼
Of course, he's going too.
当然  他也会同行
I got his whereabouts, boss.
掌握到行踪了  老大
The Nishitamashi twin towers.
西多摩市的双塔摩天大楼
That building is called the place closes to heaven.
那里好像号称是最接近天国的地方…
Perfect.
太好了
The place which is closest to heaven is perfect for an execution...
离那个世界最近  正好用来做断头台…
(Detective Conan Countdown to Heaven)
名侦探柯南  通往天国的倒计时
I am Shinichi Kudo, the high school detective.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I was at an amusement park with Ran,
当我跟青梅竹马的同学毛利兰
my childhood friend,
一起到游乐园玩时
I witnessed two men in black in the middle of a suspicious deal.
却目击了黑衣男子可疑的交易现场
At that time, I was so focused at what was happening
当时我只顾着偷看交易现场
that I ignored one of them had come up behind me.
却忽略了从背后接近的另一个同伙
I was forced to consume poison.
我被那个人强灌了毒药
When I woke up again,
等我醒来时
my body had shrunk.
我的身体已经缩小了
If they knew that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
要是让他们知道工藤新一还活着
they'll try to kill me
不但我的性命难保
and even hurt the people around me.
还会危害到我周围的亲人
So I listened to Professor Agasa's advice
在阿笠博士的建议下
and hid my true identity.
我隐瞒了身份
When Ran asked about my name,
当小兰问及我的名字时
the name Conan Edogawa suddenly hit me.
情急之下  我化名为江户川柯南
In order to get more information on those guys,
为了搜集那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran and her detective father.
于是便住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家中
I am Hiroshi Agasa, the ingenious inventor.
我就是天才发明家阿笠博士
Allow me to introduce my masterpieces.
现在来介绍我发明的杰作
The Stun-gun wristwatch.
手表型麻醉枪
The Voice-Changing Bowtie.
蝴蝶结型变声器
The Power Assisted Kick Shoes.
脚力倍增鞋
The Turbo-Engine skateboard
涡轮引擎滑板
And the Criminal Locator Glasses.
还有嫌犯追踪眼镜
I've even added a secret weapon in these glasses,
这边的镜片还加装着一项最新的秘密武器
which are night-vision telescopic lenses.
那就是  红外线望远镜功能
These were all designed for Shinichi whose body had shrunk.
这些都是专门为身体变小的新一而做的
By using these tools,
他靠着这些小道具
he has been able to mimic Mr. Mouri's voice
变成毛利的声音
to solve cases and capture criminals.
解开案子的迷底  逮捕真凶
That's right. I almost forgot.
对了  对了  差点给忘了
His classmates, the Detective Boys,
还有他的同学
have the Detective Badges.
少年侦探团所拥有的侦探徽章
Along with the watch flashlight,
还有手表型手电筒
which were all invented by me.
全都是我的杰作
Apart from me, there are four people
而知道他的真实身份的
who know about Conan's real identity,
除了我之外还有四个人
His father, Yusaku Kudo, who's a mystery novelist.
他父亲  推理小说家工藤优作
His mother, Yukiko Kudo, who used to be an actress.
他母亲  原女星工藤有希子
Heiji Hattori, who's a high school detective in Kansai.
关西的高中生侦探  服部平次
And finally Ai Haibara, his classmate.
还有他的同学灰原哀
Ai's real name is Shiho Miyano.
她本名叫宫野志保
She used to be a member of the Black Organization.
她本来跟黑暗组织是同伙的
However, after her sister, Akemi Miyano, was killed by the organization,
但在姐姐宫野明美被组织杀害后
she decided to flee from them.
她打算逃离组织时
By taking the same poison Shinichi took,
吃下了跟新一相同的毒药
her body shrunk as well.
身体也变小了
People of the Black Organization
黑暗组织那群人
have been trying to track her down.
不死心地追查着灰原的下落
Now,
而现在
somewhere hidden from me,
在我看不到的地方
a crime is being committed.
案件即将发生
Though my body was shrunken, I remain clever.
身体虽变小  但头脑一样棒
I am the famous detective who can solve all the cases.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
This seat is too cramped.
这个位子实在太挤了
It's because you're sitting in the back, Genta.
都是因为元太你坐在后座的关系啦
You were in the front seat when we came.
来的时侯你是坐在前座的啊
I thought it would be more fun in the back.
因为后座好像比较有意思嘛
Conan, move over a bit.
柯南  再挤过去一点
Come one.
真是的
Why did you eat five bowls of rice in the morning?
谁叫你一大早就吃了五碗饭
Sorry, Ayumi, let's squeeze together.
对不起  步美  再挤一点吧
Mitsuhiko, let's play a game.
光彦  来玩游戏吧
Let's play the 30-seconds game.
那么来玩"猜30秒游戏"好了
Countdown to 30 seconds without looking at a timer
在心里面数到30秒
and then push on the stop button.
就按下停止键停下秒表
Interesting, let's all play!
有意思  大家一起玩吧
I have to drive.
我得开车
I'll pass on that too.
我也放弃
28, 29, 30!
28、29、30
40 seconds! I'm off by 10 seconds.
40秒  超过10秒了
29, 30!
29、30
I got 27 seconds.
是27秒
What a pity...
真是可惜
30...
30 …
59 seconds?
59秒
Is this thing broken?
这个是不是有毛病啊
It's you that's broken.
我看有毛病的是你才对
28, 29, 30!
28、29、30
Exactly 30 seconds!
刚好30秒耶
Ayumi, you are brilliant.
步美好厉害喔
It's like you have a superpower.
简直有特异功能
It was just a coincidence.
是碰巧的啦
By the way, Haibara,
对了  灰原
who were you talking on the phone with late at night yesterday?
昨夜那么晚你跟谁讲电话啊
I didn't make a phone call.
我没有打电话啊
Kojima, maybe you were having a dream.
小岛你是不是睡迷糊了
Really?
是吗
It's so tall.
好高
I can't even see the top.
看不到顶端呢
It looks like it could reach the clouds.
简直就像升到云朵的上面一样
Isn't that Conan?
那不是柯南吗
Sister Ran.
小兰姐
What a coincidence.
怎么了呢
You brats, why are you guys here?
小鬼  你们怎么会在这里
We were going home after camping.
露营完回家
Then we decided to take a detour to see this building.
顺道绕过来看这栋大楼的
Uncle, what about you guys?
那大叔你们呢
Tokiwa Mio, the owner of this building
这栋大楼的所有者常盘美绪
is my old college friend.
是我大学的学妹
She invited me to visit a week before the opening ceremony.
在下周开幕前特别招待我来参观的
Why have I never heard about this?
怎么都没听说过呢
Me neither.
就是说啊
My dad didn't tell me about this.
爸爸连我都没讲呢
I felt he was acting strange,
我觉得怪怪的
so I had to interrogate him to get him to confess.
在逼问之下他才招认的呢
Confess... you are exaggerating...
招认…我哪有…
I see, Sister Ran and Sister Sonoko are here
原来是为了要监视大叔的行动
to keep watch on Uncle Mouri.
所以小兰姐们才来的啊
Because Tokiwa Mio is
因为这位常盘美绪
the president of the Tokiwa Corporation
可是常盘财团的大千金
and also single right now.
目前还是小姑独处
Since Ran's parents are living apart right now,
对于双亲分居的小兰来说
of course she'll feel worried.
当然会担心啊
Excuse me, are you Mr. Mouri?
抱歉  是毛利小五郎先生吗
Yes, I am.
是
I'm the president's secretary, Sawaguchi.
我是董事长的秘书泽口
She's meeting with our clients right now.
目前董事长还在接待客户
So please follow me to the showroom.
请先随我到展示室参观
This is Tower A where all the offices are.
这里的A栋  整栋都是办公区
Tokiwa Corporation uses all of the floors above the 31st floor.
31楼以上都是属于常盘财团
The showroom is on the 2nd and 3rd floor.
展示室设在2楼跟3楼
What kind of company is the Tokiwa Corporation?
常盘集团是什么样的公司啊
Tokiwa specializes in software
主要是做电脑软件的
but deals with everything concerning computers.
但只要是与电脑相关的都有做
So, they make video games too?
那也有电视游戏咯
We are going to have so much fun here.
这下有得玩了
There are so many interesting things here.
有趣的东西还真多啊
Welcome, everybody.
欢迎各位莅临
This is Mr. Hara, our executive and programmer.
他是董事兼程序设计师的原先生
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
What is this?
这是什么啊
A game machine?
是游戏机吗
Do you want to have a try?
要不要试试看
This computer
这部电脑
can predict what someone will look like in ten years.
可以预测十年后的长相
What we'll look like in ten years?
十年后的长相啊
This is awesome.
这真是厉害啊
Professor, can we?
博士  来玩吧
Why don't you two have a seat?
那么请两位坐好
I'd rather not see
我可不想看到
how aged and ugly I've become ten years later.
自己十年后衰老的臭脸…
Are you ready? Let's start.
好了吗  要开始了喔
All right, this is what you'll look like in ten years.
好  这就是两位十年后的样子
What the heck, you look exactly the same.
什么嘛  根本没变嘛
The machine must be broken.
这部机器一定是坏了
No, it doesn't seem like it.
不  没坏
Check out Ayumi's photo.
你们看步美的那张
So cute!
好可爱喔
She'll definitely be more popular than Sister Sonoko.
绝对比这位姐姐受欢迎多了
What do a bunch of brats know about the charms of an adults?
小鬼哪懂大人的魅力啊
Anyway, let's try it too!
总之我们也来玩吧
Okay!
好
Yeah, yeah! I've seen high school students who look like this.
有  有  我看到过这种高中生
Wow, the two of you look great.
哎呀  两个人都拍得很好哦
Really?
真的吗
Let's go try it too, Ran.
接下去我跟小兰了
Yeah, yeah! I've seen old ladies looking like this.
有  有  我看到过这种老太婆
Shut it you!
你吵死了
So pretty.
好美
You look just like a younger version of Eri.
长得跟年轻时的英理一模一样
Too bad you're stuck with Shinichi
跟新一在一起真的有点可惜
It bugs me to think that
一想到你竟然被那种家伙独占
you''re stuck with that guy.
真让人不爽
What are you talking about, Sonoko?
你说什么啊  园子
Come on... don't say that... ha...
不…哪有…哈…
Why are you blushing?
你干嘛脸红啊
No... I'm not...
不…没有啦…
That's not what I mean...
不是那个意思啦…
Conan and Haibara should go next...
接下来是柯南跟灰原…
Haibara!
灰原
I'll pass on that.
我不用了
So do I.
我也放弃
Of course, my face will look exactly the same as Shinichi's in the photo
在十年后我当然就会变成新一
and Haibara will become Shiho Miyano.
而灰原会变成宫野志保的样子
I'd like to see
我倒是想瞧瞧
what this wicked boy will look like ten years later!
你这个兔崽子十年后的鬼模样
Haibara, you do it too!
灰原你也一起来嘛
Wait...
等一下…
This is bad.
这下惨了
I wonder what Conan will look like.
不知道柯南会变怎样呢
Error? That's odd.
出错  奇怪了
Lucky!
运气真好
Maybe it means we'll be dead
说不定是指十年后
within ten years.
我们都不存在在这个世上了呢
Okay, understood.
好  知道了
Everyone,
各位
please follow me to the banquet venue on the 75th floor.
请随我到75楼的宴会会场
Let's walk to the elevator.
请往电梯方向走
Sorry.
对不起
It's fine...
不会…
You're at it again.
又来了
She was born on the year of the Boar, so she's always so clumsy.
她属猪的  所以总是东撞西撞
Ha... that's what it is.
哈…原来如此
So you are always like this.
你经常干这种事啊
Does this elevator go straight to the 75th floor?
这个电梯直达75楼吗
Yes.
是的
This is the VIP elevator
这是VIP贵宾专用的电梯
which has access to any floor of the building.
可以直达想去的楼层
The only other way to access this elevator
能够从外部搭这部电梯的地方
is from the concert hall on the 66th floor.
也只有66楼的音乐厅一处而已
It's so beautiful. So tall.
好美喔  好高喔
The scenery is splendid.
景色太棒了
It feels like we're going straight to heaven.
好像一步步接近天国似的
Sorry for the mess,
这里目前正在为开业宴会做准备
everything is being set up for the party.
所以多少有点杂乱
Senior Mouri!
毛利学长
Tokiwa, it's been a while.
常盘  好久不见了
Thanks for travelling all the way here.
还劳驾你从大老远前来
No, I was supposed to be here alone...
不  本来是该一个人来的…
I'm Ran, his daughter.
我是他的女儿小兰
My mom told me to say hi.
家母要我代她向你问侯
Ran.
小兰
Let me do the introduction.
我来介绍一下
This is Sonoko Suzuki, my classmate.
这位是我的同学  铃木园子
Professor Agasa, an inventor.
这位是发明家阿笠博士
Conan Edogawa,
这位是江户川柯南
Ai Haibara,
灰原哀
Ayumi Yoshida,
吉田步美
Mitsuhiko Tsuburaya,
圆谷光彦
Hello.
你好
and Genta Kojima
小岛元太
Hello everyone, I'm Tokiwa Mio.
大家好  我是常盘美绪
Please allow me to introduce my associates.
我也来介绍一下
This is my art teacher,
这位是我的绘画老师
and also a famous painter in Japan, Hosui Kisaragi.
日本画画家如月峰水先生
Hosui Kisaragi...
如月峰水…
Are you the painter who's known for painting Mount Fuji...
难道是那个以画富士山而闻名的…
I know something about you too!
我也对你略知一二呢
Are you that detective,
是不是叫作什么
Sleeping Bug Kogoro?
"瞌睡虫小五郎"侦探来的
I am 'Sleeping Kogoro'.
我是"沉睡小五郎"
This man smells of liquor.
这个大叔好重的酒臭味
This is a council member in Nishitamashi,
这位是西多摩市市议员
Iwamatsu Oki.
大木岩松先生
When we were constructing this building,
要盖这栋大楼的时侯
he gave me a lot of help.
多亏有他四处奔走帮忙呢
This is Hidehiko Kazama,
然后这位是这栋大楼的设计师
the architect who designed this building.
建筑家风间英彦先生
I believe we've met in the past, Mr. Mouri.
我跟毛利先生其实有点缘分
I actually studied under Teiji Moriya.
其实我是森谷帝二的弟子
You are a student of Teiji Moriya.
森谷帝二的
But don't worry.
不过别担心
I won't blow buildings up
我不会像森谷那样
like Moriya did.
把这栋大楼给炸毁的
Blow... blow up.
炸…炸毁
It's because the two buildings have different height
因为大楼高度不同
and are asymmetrical, right?
左右又不对称的关系  对吧
Little boy, you know a lot of things.
小朋友  你懂得还真多啊
Hurry, hurry! The view from here is great!
快  快点  可以看得很清楚呢
It's so beautiful!
好漂亮喔
So big!
好大喔
What a fantastic view!
这真是绝景啊
You can see Mount Fuji at night from this place.
这里晚上也可以看见富士山呢
At night?
晚上也可以
What does she mean?
这是什么意思
We could see Mount Fuji even at night?
就算晚上也可以看见富士山
What can we see
对面那边的窗子
from the windows over there?
又可以看见什么呢
What is that?
那是什么东西
It's like the roof of a Dome.
好像是巨蛋的屋顶
Tower B is a commercial building.
隔壁的B栋是商业大楼
The bottom floors are stores
下面是店铺
while the top is a hotel.
上面则是饭店
The top floor is home to an indoor pool
最顶楼还有室内游泳池
complete with a retractable roof.
那个巨蛋屋顶是可以开启的
How incredible!
真是了不起啊
By the way, Mio,
对了  美绪
can I stay at the hotel this weekend?
周末我可以去住那家饭店吗
But... the hotel hasn't opened yet.
可是…现在还没开幕呢
I guess that's a no, huh?
意思是不行吗
I understand.
我知道了
I'll prepare the suite on the 67th floor for you.
我会准备好67楼的套房给您
I'd like to have dinner with you
可以的话
if that's possible...
我还想跟你一起共进晚餐…
That's a very unusual brooch.
这胸针蛮特别的嘛
From a special someone, perhaps?
心上人送的东西吗
No, this is something I bought.
不是  是我自己挑选的
Mio, I'm going now!
美绪  我要回去了
Oh, let me see you off.
喔  那我送您下楼
There's no need to.
大可不必送了
He seems pretty unhappy.
看来他很不高兴耶
Mio bought Mr. Kisaragi's paintings
美绪小姐买下如月老师的画后
and sold them for a profit.
再以高价脱手
That's why he feels a bit...
所以他有点那个…
It's chocolate!
是巧克力耶
Well, since you guys saw it,
糟糕  被你们看到了
I'll give you a treat.
请你们吃一点吧
Awesome!
好棒喔
Here you are.
拿去
Thanks a lot.
不客气咯
Thank you.
谢谢
Though he's a genius programmer,
虽然他是个天才程序设计师
he's actually very childish.
但却非常的孩子气
That's why he could create interesting games.
就是这样才能写出有趣的游戏啊
That's right!
对了
I'm currently writing the software for a new game.
现在我正想写新的游戏软件
If it's possible,
可以的话
can you guys give me some advice?
请你们提供点建议给我好吗
Games?
游戏吗
No problem!
好啊
I live in Sou chou.
我住的地方在双宝町
We live in Beika chou.
我们住在米花町
So we live pretty close.
那还蛮近的耶
It would be a short journey by bus.
坐巴士很快就到了
Why don't you guys come to my house to have fun next Sunday?
下星期天到我家来玩玩吧
Okay, we'll be there!
好  我们一定到
Ai, what's wrong?
小哀  怎么了
Nothing.
没什么
Sister Ran...
小兰姐…
Actually, there's something I need to discuss with you.
其实我有点事情想跟你商量
Can we meet tomorrow?
明天可以碰个面吗
Sure.
可以啊
I'll tell you when and where later.
时间跟地点待会我再跟你说
Sister Ran, there's something I need to talk to you about in private.
小兰姐  我有件事想私下跟你说
The problem must be my haircut.
问题大概是出在发型上吧
Maybe I should get a perm.
我也来烫个波浪好了
I can't believe we can still see that car.
想不到现在还能看到那种车
What's it called?
叫什么来着
It's a Porsche 356A.
保时捷356A啦
What...
什么…
You two!
你们
That elevator is for the VIP guests only.
那部电梯是贵宾专用的
Staff members should take the elevator at the back!
员工应该搭乘背面的一般电梯
Yes... we are sorry...
是…对不起…
Where did you see that car?
那部车在哪里看到的
What's the color of it?
颜色呢
It was parked in front of the building.
刚才停在这栋大楼前面
And the color is black.
颜色是黑色的
It's Gin's car!
是琴酒的车子
Wait, Conan.
等一下  柯南
Brat, where are you going?
浑球  去哪啊
Come on, come on!
快点  快点
It's over there!
在那里
Damn it!
可恶
Why did they come to this building?
他们怎么会来这栋大楼
In fact, I've been having a crush on Ayumi since kindergarten.
其实我从幼稚园开始就喜欢步美了
But Ayumi seems to like Conan.
可是步美好像很喜欢柯南
Sister Ran, can you please tell me
小兰姐  请你告诉我好吗
how can Ayumi and I
要怎么做
turn into a couple from childhood friends
才能像你跟新一哥哥一样
like you and Brother Shinichi did?
又是青梅竹马又是情侣呢
Wait... Shinichi and I aren't...
等等…我跟新一又没…
Also, I've started to like Haibara too...
而且最近我也开始在意灰原…
Am I a horrible guy
同时喜欢上两位女性的我
for liking two girls?
是不是很糟糕的男生啊
You are not a horrible person.
才不是糟糕呢
It's a good thing to have someone you like.
喜欢上一个人是很好的事情
I think you should cherish those feelings.
我也觉得应该珍惜这样的感觉
Then...
那…
But don't you think
不过现在你们还继续做好朋友
it's good to stay as friends for now?
不是也很好吗
Whether it's Ayumi or Harbara?
不管是步美或是小哀
And also with Conan and Genta.
柯南跟元太当然也是
I see.
我明白了
Get five donuts
从现在起买甜甜圈五个
and enjoy a fifty percent discount.
半价优待
Welcome.
欢迎光临
I like Conan so much.
我好喜欢柯南
But Conan has a crush on someone else.
可是柯南却另外有喜欢的人了
Do you mean Haibara?
难道说是小哀吗
No. It's you, sister Ran
不是  是小兰姐啦
It can't be.
不会吧
Conan must have fallen in love with you. I'm sure.
柯南一定是喜欢上小兰姐了  绝对
So I hope you could tell him that
所以我希望小兰姐告诉柯南
you already have Shinichi as your boyfriend.
说你已经有一个叫新一的男朋友了
Please tell him to give up.
请他快点死心吧
Well...
这…
Otherwise, Conan will be so pathetic.
不然的话  柯南就太可怜了
But we don't know whether
可是又没有确定
Conan likes me.
柯南真的是喜欢我啊
I know!
我知道的
How?
为什么
A woman's intuition!
女人的直觉
Rea... really?
是…是吗
What?
什么
I said that Conan has a crush on me.
就是柯南好像喜欢上我了啦
That's absurd.
你胡说些什么啊
He doesn't like you at all, you fool.
才没有喜欢你呢  笨蛋
How would you know?
你怎么知道呢
Well...
没有啦
Kids having a crush on someone is as common as having the measles.
小孩子的恋爱就像出麻疹一样
It's nothing to worry about.
没什么好大惊小怪的啦
Can you be serious about this matter?
你认真一点行不行啊
Then, don't lie to yourself
那你就不要随便欺骗自己
and be honest with yourself.
诚实地面对吧
Be honest with myself?
诚实地面对自己
If you do that,
这样的话
you'll find the answer yourself.
大概就可以靠自己找到答案了
That's all for now. I'll call you alter on.
就这样了  我再打电话给你
Sigh.
唉
I'm the one who should be honest with myself...
该诚实面对自己的应该是我吧…
(Nishitamashi Twin Towers)
[西多摩市双塔摩天大楼]
(67th floor suite of Tower B)
[B栋67楼套房]
What... what do you want...
干…干什么…
I called you guys here
找你们来不为别的
because we found a murder victim
在双塔摩天大楼的套房里
in the suite of the twin towers.
发现了遭刺杀身亡的尸体
That man is...
这个人…
Iwamatsu Oki, a council member in Nishitamashi.
西多摩市市议员大木岩松
I heard that when he asked Tokiwa Mio to arrange a room for him,
在他向常盘美绪要求住宿时
you guys happened to be there.
听说你们刚好都在旁边
Chiba.
千叶
Yes.
是
The time of death is
大木的死亡时间
between ten o'clock at night to midnight.
大概是晚上十点到凌晨零点之间
The murder weapon is suspected to be a knife. But we didn't find it at the scene.
凶器可能是刀  但现场没找到
However, Oki had in his hand,
但是大木的手上
a sake cup that was broken in half.
握着被一分为二的小酒杯
Sake cup?
小酒杯
This one.
就是这个
This cup is very expensive.
这小酒杯是属于高价品
Oki likes to drink a lot.
大木很喜欢喝酒
Perhaps he brought it there with sake.
很可能是跟日本酒一起带来的
However, we believe that
我们认为
it's the victim's message
很可能是死者用来暗示犯人的
to suggest the identity of the murderer.
死亡讯息
In order words, the police think that
换句话说警方认为
the murderer is one of those five.
嫌疑犯是那五个人之一咯
That's because the building isn't open to the public yet.
因为现场是还没有正式开放的新大楼
I know!
我明白了
Sake cup (ochoko) means chocolate (choko)!
小酒杯[ochoko]指的是巧克力[choko]
So the murderer must be
凶手就是
Hara Yoshiaki who likes chocolate!
喜欢吃巧克力的原佳明
No way!
骗人
It can't be Mr. Hara!
才不是原先生呢
Because he gave his chocolate to us!
因为原先生还分巧克力给我们吃
He's a good guy!
他是个好人呢
Stay out of it you kids!
吵死了
Mr. Hara should be innocent.
原先生应该是清白的
We questioned the five of them
我们传讯过了他们五人
and he's the only one who had an alibi.
其中只有他有不在场证明
Alibi...
不在场证明…
Come on, Inspector Megure,
目暮警官也真是的
why didn't you say that early?
这种事情早点说嘛
Sake cup.
小酒杯
It means to be worried (ochokochoi).
指的是慌慌张张[ochokochoi]吗
If that's the case, then the most suspicious person
那样的话  最可疑的
would be Mr. Mouri, right?
不就是毛利先生了吗
Shiratori...
白鸟…
I'm just joking.
开玩笑的啦
Seriously.
真是的
What about the motive?
那动机方面呢
It's still under investigation.
现在还在调查中
Although Oki was just a council member,
虽然大木是市议员
he seemed to have greater power
但实际上似乎握有
than the mayor.
比市长更大的权力
An example would be the Twin Tower Buildings.
像这次的双塔摩天大楼也是
The municipal law which opposes high-rise building projects
将原本不允许建设高层建筑的
was overturned because of him.
市级条例强行修改后通过的
That's why Miss. Mio couldn't reject Mr. Oki's request of
所以美绪才无法拒绝大木提出
living in the hotel before the opening ceremony.
在开幕前的酒店住宿的要求啊
Come to think of it,
这么说来
doesn't the brooch which Mio wore
美绪小姐所佩带的胸针
look a lot like this broken cup?
不是跟这个碎了的小酒杯很像吗
Wait, it can't be Mio...
等一下  绝对不会是美绪…
No, considering the success rate of the murder,
不  以犯罪的成功率来讲的话
she's the current main suspect.
她是最有嫌疑的人
That's because Mr. Oki lived
因为大木先生住宿的
on the 67th floor of Tower B.
B栋67楼的楼上
While she stayed on the 68th floor.
68楼正是她的住处
No way...
哪有这样的…
That sake cup reminds me of the bowl
那个小酒杯跟画日本画时
used for Japanese painting.
用的小碟子好像有点像喔
My dad is also interested in Japanese paintings.
我爸爸的兴趣也是画日本画
This sake cup is like the bowl
这跟在捣碎胡粉时
used to mix powder.
所用的乳钵很像
It seems like Mr. Kisaragi
看来如月跟小酒杯
is relevant to the sake cup too...
真的有关连性…
But Mr. Kazama and Miss. Sawaguchi seem to
可是在泽口和风间身上都找不到
have nothing to do with the sake cup.
和小酒杯有关的共通之处
Officer Shiratori,
白鸟刑事
is Mr. Kazama really a student of Teiji Moriya?
风间真的是森谷帝二的弟子吗
Yeah.
真的啊
But he's unlike Moriya who's an artist
不过他跟艺术家型的森谷不同
and more of a tech guy.
他是搞技术出身的
So he's really not a perfectionist like Moriya.
几乎没有什么坚持
As for Sawaguchi Chinami,
关于泽口知奈美
her father is a journalist
她的父亲是一名新闻记者
who died from exhaustion on her senior year of college.
在她大四那一年因过度劳累去逝
But so far,
可是到目前为止
we didn't find her connection with Oki.
还没发现她和大木有什么关连
Inspector Megure,
目暮警官
The reason why the crime took place in the hotel which hasn't opened...
这起案子之所以选在开幕前的酒店…
The blood splatter is only on the lower part of the closet
血只有溅到衣柜下面的地方
with a very unnatural shape.
而且飞溅的形状也很不自然
This is not something a child should look at.
这不是小孩子该看的东西喔
Okay.
是
Besides, why did Gin and Vodka
而且  琴酒跟伏特加
go to the twin towers...
为什么要来双塔摩天大楼…
Wait...
等等…
The sake cup could be connected with alcohol.
由小酒杯可以联想到的是酒
Haibara, could it be them...
灰原  难不成是他们…
Their code names are all based on alcoholic beverages.
的确他们的代号都是酒名
But they wouldn't do something so stupid,
但是留下那么直接的暗号的愚蠢行为
leaving such obvious note at the crime scene.
他们是不会做的
Tomorrow we...
我们明天…
How about that?
就这样  可以吧
Mitsuhiko, over here!
光彦  这里  这里
You two are early.
你们两个真早啊
I'm so excited!
觉得好兴奋喔
I feel so happy that we could dump Conan
想到能甩掉柯南行动
and act on our own.
就觉得好高兴喔
Who did say you want to dump?
你说甩掉谁啊
He's here!
出现了
How... how did you find out?
你…你怎么会知道的
It's too easy to
太明显了啦
guess the plan you had in mind.
你们在想的事情
You must be thinking
反正你们一定在想
I'll say it's too dangerous for you to investigate by yourselves
这次如果你们要自己单独调查的话
and stop you guys.
我一定会说很危险而阻止你们
Right?
对吧
That's... correct...
答…答对了…
I'll let this slide this time.
这次就算了
But don't ever do this again.
往后可不能擅自行动喔
Okay!
知道了
Did they really listen?
他们真的知道了吗
So, where are we going today?
那  今天要去谁那里
We are going to find Mr. Kazama and Mr. Kisaragi.
风间先生和如月先生那边
Tomorrow, we'll go to Mr. Hara's place.
明天再去原先生家
Though Mr. Kazama's home is at Setagaya,
风间先生的家虽然在世田谷
he has a workshop near Asahino station
可是他在西多摩车站前一站的
which is only one stop ahead of Nishitamashi station.
朝日野那边有个工作室
He will be staying there
到双塔摩天大楼正式启用为止
until the twin towers is put into operation.
他好像都会在那里
Mr. Kisaragi is single.
而如月先生则是单身
Three years ago, he built a house
并在三年前在朝日野
which he uses as a workshop and also his residence in Asahino.
建了一栋工作室兼住宅的房子
They did some good investigating.
调查得还相当仔细嘛
If we knew Conan would come,
早知道这样
we should've convinced Haibara to come as well.
灰原也一起来就好了
You already asked Haibara to join you?
你们也找灰原了吗
Yes.
对啊
But she said she would be busy with housework today,
可是她说今天要打扫房间很忙
so she couldn't come.
所以不来
Brother!
哥哥
This is what will happen to a traitor...
反正背叛者的下场就是这样…
Brother, brother!
哥哥  哥哥
The apartment which Mr. Kazama rented
风间先生租的公寓
should be near the bus station.
应该就在车站附近
And Mr. Kisaragi's house
而如月先生的家…
might be on that hill.
大概在那个山丘上吧
First, let's head to Mr. Kazama's apartment.
首先到风间先生的公寓去吧
This is a CAD system, right?
这是CAD系统吧
You design everything with this computer, right?
设计全部都是用电脑做的吧
I'm surprised that you know that.
你还蛮清楚的嘛
No one uses
现在应该已经没有人
drawing boards anymore.
用制图板了吧
What is a drawing board?
制图板是什么
Ha... right.
哈…这样啊
You wouldn't know what a drawing board is.
你们反而不知道制图板啊
We used to attach a paper
以前都是在一个大板子上
on a large board.
贴一张纸
Then we use pencils and compasses to draw the plans.
然后再用铅笔和圆规在纸上设计
I see.
是这样的啊
By the way, why was it you wanted to see me?
对了  你们找我有什么事
Ask him, quick.
你快问啦
Me?
我吗…
You are the one who gathered us together.
是你先找大家的耶
Fine... all right.
我…我知道了啦
Actually, Mr. Kazama, we...
其实风间先生  我们…
You have a nice apartment.
你的房子相当不错嘛
The air is fresh here and you can see Mount Fuji.
空气又好  又看得到富士山
This is not going to work...
这样不行啦…
We are known as the Detective Boys.
我们是少年侦探团
We're currently investigating
我们在调查大木先生
the death of Mr. Oki.
被杀害的事件
You guys are so brave.
你们还真是勇敢啊
All right, you can ask anything you want,
好吧  要问什么都可以
young detectives.
各位小侦探们
So...
那么…
What do you think of
对于死去的大木先生这个人
Mr. Oki who has passed away?
你觉得他怎么样呢
That's very blunt.
还真是一针见血啊
A filthy middle-aged man.
下流的中年人吧
Anyway, thanks to his influence in the city council,
不过  多亏他修改了条例
I have my job.
我也因此得到了工作
So I thank him for that.
所以在这方面我很感谢他喔
During the process of designing,
在进行设计时
did you have any disagreements with Mr. Oki?
有跟大木先生发生纠纷吗
No, not with Mr. Oki.
跟大木先生没有耶
Which mean you quarreled with someone else.
那有跟其他人发生不愉快咯
No... that's not what I mean.
不…我不是那个意思啦
That photo...
那张照片…
That's my only child.
那是我的独生子
He's cute, isn't he?
很可爱吧
When I work alone at night,
像晚上一个人工作的时侯
I would always want to hear his voice.
总会想听听他的声音…
So sometimes I would call him,
明知道他已经睡了
even though I know he's asleep.
还是会打电话给他
Parents are silly, right?
做父母的真的很傻  对吧
Me?
我
Well... we are the Detective Boys.
这个…我们是少年侦探团
And we'd like to ask you about Mr. Oki's murder...
我们想请教一下大木先生的案子…
Kid's shouldn't try to imitate the police!
小孩子不要学警察办什么案
No... we...
不…我们…
Though,
不过话说回来
I don't want you to go back empty handed.
空着手不好回去吧…
Let me give you something.
给你们好东西当礼物吧
I'm glad that he gave us his paintings,
虽然说帮我们画画是很高兴啦
but we didn't ask him anything about the case.
却没敢问跟案件有关的事
So we can't do it because we are not the police?
难道不是警察就不行了吗
That's right.
就是这么一回事
It's almost six o'clock.
已经六点了
Let's call it a day.
今天就到此为止吧
What's that sound?
刚刚那是什么声音
Oh, it was my snoring.
原来是我打鼾的声音啊
Haibara was on the phone last night?
灰原半夜在打电话
When we went camping last time,
之前去露营的时侯
Genta mentioned something similar.
元太不就说过了吗
It seems she did make a phone call then.
看来那时她也是在打电话
But...
可是…
There should be no one
现在她已经没有人
she could phone.
可以打电话了才对
I trust her.
我是相信她啦
But what if her fear for the Black Organization
可是对那些黑暗组织的恐惧感
drove her back to that organization.
或许会迫使她再回到组织去
It's fine, Professor.
没事的  博士
There's nothing to worry about.
什么都不用担心
Bye.
就这样
Good morning, everyone.
大家好早啊
Morning, Conan.
早安  柯南
You are so slow!
你好慢喔
We've been waiting for so long!
等你好久了
Haibara is going to Mr. Hara's home with us.
灰原也要跟我们去原先生家
Oh really...
这样啊…
Can I go too?
可以吧
I'm also interested in
因为我也有兴趣啊
the games at Mr. Hara's home.
原先生家的游戏…
Apartment 407.
407号房
This is Mr. Hara's apartment.
原先生的房间在这里
The door's open.
门是开着的哦
He's so careless.
真是粗心啊
Mr. Hara, we are here...
原先生  我们来了…
Co... Conan, Mr. Hara, he...
柯…柯南  原先生他…
Call the police and an ambulance!
快叫警察跟救护车
He was shot in the chest and killed instantly.
被枪射中胸部  当场死亡
A knife...
刀子…
Was he going to eat some cake?
是打算要吃蛋糕吗
This is...
这是…
A sake cup.
小酒杯
That means...
也就是说…
it's the same criminal.
是同一个凶手
What do you think, coroner?
怎么样  验尸官
I can't say for sure until the autopsy.
还没有解剖所以还不清楚
The time of death should be between
推定的死亡时间应该是
yesterday afternoon to evening.
昨天的下午到傍晚这段时间吧
Mr. Hara seemed to have been ready
原先生本来好像是
to eat this chocolate cake.
准备要吃巧克力蛋糕的样子
The murderer came at that time,
这时凶手来到这里
so he used the knife for cutting cake to
所以他才打算用切蛋糕用的银刀
fight the murderer.
和凶手对抗吧
But...
可是…
How do you explain the sake cup?
这个小酒杯要怎么解释才好
That's easy.
那还用说吗
It's from the same person who killed Mr. Oki.
是由杀害大木先生的同一个凶手犯下的
This person is a serial killer.
连续杀人事件啊
If that's the case,
不过这样的话这个小酒杯
the cup was not a message from the victim
并非被害者死前所留下的死亡讯息
but it is very likely now
而是凶手刻意留下的暗示的
they are hints left by the killer
可能性也提高了
Hi Kids.
小朋友
Officer, are you finished?
警察先生  已经好了吗
Yeah.
对啊
By the way,
对了
I heard that you all found the body.
听说你们是第一目击者
Yeah, it was scary...
对啊  吓了一大跳…
Is that the sake cup at the crime scene?
那就是现场的小酒杯吗
Yeah, that's right.
对  没错
Odd. There's no blood stain on the broken pieces...
奇怪  碎片都没有沾到血…
Officer, are all the pieces here?
警察先生  碎片全都在这了吗
Of course.
当然咯
The Crime Scene Team wouldn't miss anything.
鉴识科的警察是不会放过任何东西的
See you then.
那我走了
Now you believe they aren't the culprits, right?
这样你就明白凶手不是他们了吧
They wouldn't leave that kind of thing there.
他们不会把那种东西留在这儿的
According to the autopsy, we know that the victim was likely killed
由解剖的结果知道了大约的死亡时间
between five and six last evening.
是昨天傍晚的五点至六点之间
Also, all the data on Mr. Hara's computer
此外  原先生电脑里的资料
have been wiped.
也全都被删除掉了
That could be one of the killer's motives.
说不定这也是杀人的动机之一
Mr. Kisaragi was innocent
五点至六点与柯南他们见面的
because he met with Conan and the other kids between 5 and 6 o'clock.
如月先生是清白的
However,
而另一方面
if Mr. Kazama drove to the crime scene
风间先生在柯南他们回去后
right after Conan and the others left,
马上开车赶来的话
he would have had the time to commit the murder.
就跟犯案时间吻合了
Then... what about Miss. Mio?
那么…美绪小姐呢
Miss Tokiwa and Miss Sawaguchi, her secretary,
常盘小姐跟秘书泽口小姐
both have solid alibi.
都没有明确的不在场证明
Mouri, sorry to say this.
虽然对毛利老弟不好意思
But the killer would be either
可是我想凶手应该就是
Tokiwa Mio, Hidehiko Kazama
常盘美绪  风间英彦
or Sawaguchi Chinami.
或是泽口知奈美其中的一人
Also, we believe that the killer is very likely to
而且我认为凶手今后
go on a killing spree.
也还极有可能会继续犯案
That's why INspector Megure asked Miss Tokiwa to
所以目暮警部想劝常盘小姐
postpone the opening party on Saturday.
把星期六的宴会延期
But she refused firmly.
可是她却一点都听不进去
Not only that, I also received this.
不只是那样  我还收到这个
Isn't this the invitation to the party?
这不是宴会的邀请函吗
Conan and I are invited,
而且我跟柯南
as well as the other kids.
还有其他孩子的名字都有耶
We are invited too?
我们也…
Seriously, what is she thinking?
真是的  她到底在想什么啊
Boss,
大哥
is this the room?
是这间房间吗
The building manager confirmed it was her from the picture.
刚给管理员看过相片确认过了
So she has been hiding in this place behind our back.
这家伙竟然背着组织躲在这种地方
She paid a full year in advance
房租预付了一年的
and the phone has been used to receive messages.
电话也一直都是电话留言
According to the neighbors,
根据隔壁邻居的说法
the phone would sometimes ring
有时会有电话打来
and a message is left
而且会在电话里留言
However, when I was about to hear those messages,
可是当我刚要听电话留言时
I found something weird.
却发现一件怪事
The messages weren't recorded.
留言并没有被录音
Who is it? What does that person want...
到底是谁想干什么…
A woman is a woman after all.
女人毕竟就是女人
There's a computer in the car. Go get it.
车子里有电脑  去拿来
This is a tracing program
里面有组织新开发的
developed by the organization.
逆向追踪程序
With this,
用那玩意的话
we will be able to trace the call in 20 seconds.
只要20秒就可以逆向追踪了
I see.
知道了
I'm Miyano.
我是宫野
I'm not at home right now.
现在不在家
Please leave your name and message
请在提示音之后
after the beep.
留下您的大名和事由
Sister, it's me.
姐姐  是我
The day after tomorrow,
后天要参加
I'll attend the opening ceremony of the twin towers.
双塔摩天大楼的开幕典礼
(Unable to trace)
[无法探知]
Kudo...
工藤…
I knew it, you've been calling your sister.
果然你是打电话给你姐姐
You've been calling the apartment
打到你姐姐宫野明美
which your sister rented secretly when she was alive.
生前偷偷租的房间里的电话
It explains the matter.
原来如此
You wanted to hear your sister's voice.
你是想跟死去的姐姐说话
It's not that I don't understand you feelings,
我不是不了解你的心情
but it's too dangerous...
可是不管怎么说都太危险…
No one would understand my feelings!
我的心情谁也不会了解的
Haibara!
灰原
Hold on.
等一下
Let's just leave her alone now.
现在让她一个人静静吧
Damn it, we were so close!
可恶  还差几秒就成功了
Boss.
老大
I'm Miyano. I'm not at home right now...
我是宫野  现在不在家…
The message was erased.
留言被消掉了
Did that woman find out that we are here?
难道那个女的感觉到我们在这里
No, she didn't.
不  不会的
She deleted the messages
她之所以会消掉留言
because she didn't want it to be heard by anyone.
也许是因为不想之后被谁听到
She has no idea
至于我们竟然在电话旁边偷听
we are listening to her by the phone.
她大概连作梦也想不到吧
Will she call again?
她还会再打来吗
I don't think she will.
应该不会再打来了吧
Anyway, I feel that even God is helping us now.
不过  我总觉得老天似乎在帮我们
On the opening ceremony of the twin towers...
双塔摩天大楼的开幕典礼
I can finally meet you, Sherry.
终于可以见到你了  雪莉
I will see your pale and rigid face after you die...
看到你那死后僵硬发青的脸…
I'm sorry for what happened last night.
昨晚对不起
I know it's a dangerous thing to do
我也知道那样做是很危险的
and that I have to change that habit.
也知道得把这习惯改掉才行
Even so,
虽说如此
I still pick up the phone without knowing
可是只要一个人觉得寂寞
when I feel lonely
害怕得不得了的时侯
and very scared.
就会不自觉地拿起电话筒
I just want to hear my sister's voice,
只想听听不到十秒的
even for less than ten seconds...
姐姐的声音…
You fool,
笨蛋
you are not alone.
你可不是一个人喔
I think it's about time I had stopped doing this anyways.
我想也差不多该是时侯了
I won't do it again.
我不会再做了
I already deleted the messages,
我已经把留言消掉了
so you don't have to worry.
所以你不用担心
However, I've been wondering lately.
可是  最近我常在想
Who am I?
我到底是谁
Where do I belong...
我的容身之处在哪里…
I have no place to stay...
哪里都没有可以容纳我的位子…
Haibara said that she didn't have a place to stay.
灰原说她没有位子
What are you talking about, Haibara?
你在说什么啊  灰原
Isn't that your seat?
你的位子不是好好地在那里吗
My seat is here.
我的位子在这
Mine is here.
我的在这
Mine here.
这里是我的
See, I told you that you were not alone.
看吧  都说了你不是一个人嘛
The wealthy lady still hasn't come?
财阀的大小姐还没来啊
She said that she already set off.
刚才她说已经出门了啦
I'm so excited about the party.
宴会真令人期待呢
I bet there will be a lot of delicious food.
一定有很多好吃的东西
I want to eat grilled eel over rice.
我想吃鳗鱼饭
I don't think they'll have that...
我想应该没有那种东西才对…
Is it possible that Hara
原董事跟黑衣人他们是同伙
worked for the Black Organization too?
有没有这个可能
It is possible.
有可能
They have been selecting talented young people
他们从以前
from the financial, medical
就常在财政界和医学界
and chemical fields
还有化学界等圈子
since a long time ago.
找一些未来很有前途的年轻人
What about Mr. Oki, the council member?
那市议员大木先生呢
Though he was not talented enough
虽然实力还有点不够
he was young indeed...
不过还算年轻…
Anyway,
不管怎么说
the organization
一旦加入组织的话
will kill anyone who tries to flee
对于想要退出的或是背叛者
or betray the organization
等待他们的都是
without mercy.
毫不留情的死亡制裁
Just like how they are hunting me.
就像他们要杀我一样
So, if the murderer is
这么说  如果凶手就是
among the four people...
那四个人其中之一的话…
That's right. Then it's very likely that the murder
没错  那家伙和组织
has something to do with the Black Organization.
有关系的可能性极高
Hi, sorry everyone!
嗨  让大家久等了
Sonoko,
园子
what happened to your hair?
你的头发是怎么回事
I felt like changing my style.
换个感觉啦
I got my hair permed like she did.
我是学她把头发烫成波浪的喔
How do I look? Is it pretty?
怎么样  好看吗
You seem to have something to say.
你好像有什么话想说喔
No... nothing!
没…没有啊
You were admiring Sister Sonoko.
刚才看园子姐姐看到发呆了
Is that so, Conan?
真的吗  柯南
No, I didn't...
不  不是啦…
Maybe I need to get a perm too.
我也去烫个波浪吧
Inspector, we should also go to the party.
警官  我们也去宴会会场吧
No.
不行
Since Miss Tokiwa rejected our proposal,
既然常盘小姐拒绝了
we can to stay here.
我们就只能在这里待命了
Now we can only pray that
现在只能祈祷
nothing would happen...
别发生什么事才好…
Caviar, foie gras and roast duck!
鱼子酱配上鹅肝酱  还有烤鸭肉
I'm gonna go mad!
我快受不了啦
I want this too!
那我也要这个
No, Professor, you should only have Japanese dishes.
不行  博士只能吃日式料理
I'll go get some low-calorie food for you.
我去帮你拿低卡路里的食物来
That girl is like your wife.
这孩子怎么好像你太太啊
Thanks to her, I'm always starving.
托她的福我常饿肚子呢
What a cool car!
好酷的车哦
This is a Ford Mustang Convertible.
这是福特的MUSTANG CONVERTIBLE耶
But, how did they transport
可是这么大一台
such a big car here?
怎么搬来这里的啊
They must have disassembled the car first
一定是把零件分解后
and reassembled it here.
再到这里组装的
No.
不是啦
They used the cargo elevator.
是用货运电梯运上来的啦
A cargo elevator?
货运电梯
There is one in the building I live.
我们家的大楼也有喔
It's larger than regular elevators.
比普通电梯还大
It's easy to transport a closet with that.
所以搬衣橱也很简单
Can an elephant fit in there?
那大象也行吗
I guess so.
我想是可以搬啦
No one would keep an elephant as a pet.
应该没有人养大象吧
It's so beautiful.
好美喔
That's right. If I could watch such splendid scenery
对啊  这么美好的景色
with Shinichi,
如果能跟新一一起看的话
I'll be so...
我该多么的…
That's what you are thinking, right?
对吧
What the hell are you talking about? Stop poking fun at me!
说什么啊  你欺负我
Actually, the original plan was to have the other building
其实  本来是想让另一幢大楼
provide a view of Mount Fuji as well.
也看得到富士山的
However, that couldn't be accomplished
可是因为地基的关系
due to the foundations.
所以无法实现
I see.
原来如此
So we can't see Mount Fuji in Tower B.
从B栋看不到富士山啊…
Everyone, thank you for
各位今天特地抽空参加常盘集团
taking your time to attend the opening party of
双塔摩天大楼开幕典礼
Tokiwa Corporation's twin towers.
在此非常感谢大家
Now, for entertainment,
在这里  作为余兴节目
I would like to invite everyone for a little game.
想请各位来玩个小游戏
I learned this game
这游戏是取自于
from my father, Tokiwa Kannari.
先父常盘金成的名字
And in order to celebrate
而且  还有为了庆祝
the 30th anniversary of Tokiwa Corporation,
常盘集团成立30周年
we'll play the game which is related to time.
所以我想玩个和时间有关的游戏
The 30-seconds game.
也就是猜30秒的游戏
That's the game Mitsuhiko showed us.
跟光彦想的一样嘛
Whoever manages a perfect 30 seconds
正好猜中的人
or comes closest
或是猜得最接近的人
will bring that Mustang Convertible
展示在那里的那辆 MUSTANG CONVERTIBLE
back home.
就当礼物让您开回家
Awesome!
好棒
The prize is the car.
是车子耶
It's a foreign convertible!
是CONVERTIBLE的进口车耶
That is so cool.
很酷耶
However, if there is a tie,
不过  如果有两人猜中的话
the winner will be decided by rock-paper-scissors
就以猜拳来决定
and the loser will have to make do
输的人就只好将就一下
and receive this mountain bike and helmet.
骑这台附安全帽的越野登山车
I prefer the mountain bike.
我比较喜欢越野登山车
Me too.
我也是
Because we can't drive.
因为我们不会开车
Excellent, Mitsuhiko!
太好了  光彦
We have Ayumi here.
反正有步美在我们就不用怕
The winner will definitely be us!
简直就是赢定了
Conan... where are you?
柯南…你在哪里啊
Anyone who wants to participate the game,
要参加游戏的人
please hand in your watch.
请先寄放您的手表
Later, we'll present you a gem
稍后我们会依各位手表的价值
which has the same value as your watch.
再送一颗等值的宝石给您
Amazing, she said gem!
好棒喔  她说是宝石耶
Tokiwa Corporation sure is loaded.
常盘财团还真是大手笔呢
Here, please take a flag.
来  放进去之后要拿一根旗子喔
Here.
请
I'll pass.
我不用了
Me too.
我也是
I didn't wear a watch today, neither do I want to participate in the game.
我没带手表  也不想参加游戏
All the kids, please come to the front
小朋友们请到前面
so we could see you.
可以看得见的地方来吧
Huh? Conan and Haibara, are you guys not playing?
怎么  柯南跟灰原不玩吗
Now, let's get ready.
那么  要开始了
After she says 'Start', each one of you should start counting,
在她说"开始"后  各位数到30秒时
and raise your flag when you think 30 seconds have passed.
就请把旗子举起来
Let's do this!
来吧
Ready, start!
预备  开始
8, 9, 10... 15, 16...
8  9  10…  15  16…
21, 22, 23...
21  22  23…
6, 7, 8... 8, 9, 10...
6  7  8…  8  9  10…
7, 8, 9...
7  8  9…
24, 25, 26...
24  25  26…
Shoot, I lost count!
惨了  我忘了数到多少了
All right.
好
I'm done.
好了
Anyway, I'll just go with them...
不行  那就跟别人一起…
Okay!
好
Okay, the guest who raised the blue flag.
好  那边拿蓝色旗子的来宾
Congratulations, you have won!
恭喜您  您中奖了
Dad!
老爸
Really?
真的假的
If it isn't Senior Mouri.
是毛利学长吧
Please come over here.
请到这边来
Excuse me.
对不起
Everyone,
各位
the winner is Kogoro Mouri, the famous detective.
得奖者是名侦探毛利小五郎
Let's hear his speech.
我们来请他说句话吧
I could finally say goodbye to
这下终于可以跟
rental cars!
租车生涯说再见了
Come on, dad.
老爸真是的
We lost.
失败了
I counted to only 25.
我才数到25秒
I thought it was only 12 seconds.
我也才数到12秒而已
I get it, next time please...
知道了  那请下次务必…
Excuse me, Mr. Kazama. Would you come with me please?
抱歉  风间先生麻烦你一下
Sorry.
抱歉
Everyone, allow me to introduce our
各位  接下来介绍
very special guest of the night.
今天最重要的贵宾
Introducing the most famous painter of Japan,
也是我国国宝级的日本画巨匠
Mr. Kisaragi and his masterpiece!
如月峰水先生的作品
Mr. Kisaragi loves Mount Fuji.
如月先生特别喜欢富士山
He spent more than 30 years
他花了30年以上的时间
painting the majestic Mount Fuji.
描绘富士山的雄姿
And now, to commemorate
这次他为了要庆祝他的学生
Tokiwa Mio's Twin Tower Building
常盘美绪的双塔摩天大楼落成
he presents his newest work!
特别赠送了一幅他的新作
Please put your hands together for
让我为各位介绍
the 'Mount Fuji with Spring Snow.'
"春雪的富士"
That's...
那是…
What?
什么
President!
董事长…
Damn it!
可恶
Let her down.
放下来
Get her down!
快把美绪小姐放下来
Close the curtains!
还有布幕也快拉起来
Yes!
是
She's gone.
不行了
The pearl necklace was hooked up to piano wire.
珍珠项链钩着钢琴线
And the piano wire is
然后钢琴线
connected to the painting...
又跟那幅画连在一起…
That is...
那是…
a sake up?
那不是小酒杯吗
Does this mean that the killer...
难道这次的事件也是…
What did you say? Tokiwa Mio was also...
你说什么  常盘美绪她…
Let's go!
快走
The painting of Mount Fuji...
富士山的画…
You can see Mount Fuji here at night too.
这里晚上也看得到富士山喔
So that's what she meant.
那句话原来是这个意思啊
So the necklace which Mio wore
也就是说美绪戴的项链
was attached to the piano wire's hook.
被带有钩子的钢琴线钩住
By passing it through the back,
而绕过后方通路的钢琴线
she was raised up
在画降下来的同时
when the painting lowered.
就把美绪给拉上去了
I see.
原来如此
Who was on the stage at that time?
那时候有谁在舞台上呢
Mr. Kisaragi and I.
我和如月先生
Please stand over there.
那么请你站到那里
Chiba, you stand at Tokiwa's place.
千叶你站到常盘的位置
Okay.
好的
Using these lights to mark our positions,
以这个灯为准
Mio stood in the middle,
在正中间的是美绪
I was here.
我在这里
You were not on the stage at that time, right?
那时候泽口小姐在舞台边对吧
Yes, I was responsible for raising the painting.
对  我在那里操纵画的升降
What about the pearl necklace.
那珍珠项链呢
She said it was a gift from someone.
她有说过是某人送的礼物
But we don't know who.
但不知道是谁…
When was this painting transported here?
这幅画是什么时候运到的
Last night.
昨晚运到的
Under Mr. Ksaragi's supervision,
当时在如月先生的监督下
we carried it inside.
我们一起搬进来的
That means,
也就是说  最有机会把
the person most likely to attach the piano wire was...
钢琴线事先绑在画上的人是…
Sorry, I know nothing.
很可惜  我也不知道
Speaking of which, Mr. Kisaragi,
说到这个  如月先生
I heard that you were mad at Mio
我听说你因为美绪买下
because she made a profit
你的画之后再以高价卖出一事
with your paintings.
感到很生气对吧
I wouldn't kill her because of that.
我才不会因为那种事就去杀人
Besides, according to what you just said,
而且从你刚刚说的那些话听来
the one who did this should be a serial killer.
这应该是连续杀人事件吧
If that's the case,
如果真如你所说的话
I had an alibi
那第二件原先生的案子发生时
when Mr. Hara was murdered.
我有不在场证明
Doesn't it mean that I'm not the murderer?
不就说明了我不是凶手吗
We didn't show Mr. Kisaragi
我们没有让如月先生看过
the sake cups in the other crime scenes.
前两次事件的小酒杯
So, it shouldn't be possible for him to put a sake cup there
所以伪装成连续杀人事件
and frame the serial killer for this.
放个相似的小酒杯这种事他应该无法做到
Excuse me,
不好意思
when the lights were dimmed,
在现场变暗的时候
I recall someone running toward Mio
我感觉好像有人跑到美绪那里
and saying something to her.
并且跟她说了些什么
Really?
真的吗
Was that person a male or female?
是男的还是女的
There was a faint smell of the perfume at that time.
我那时有闻到淡淡的香水味
Yeah, it was me!
是  那个人是我
But... but...
可…可是…
I went there to
我是为了跟董事长
confirm the next program with the president.
确认接下来的程序才过去的
Inspector Megure,
目暮警部
I think I know who the murderer is!
我知道凶手是谁了
It's you, Sawaguchi Chinami!
凶手就是你  泽口知奈美
No... no, why do you think it's me?
不…不是  为什么是我
Miss Sawaguchi,
泽口小姐
I heard that your father was
我听说你的父亲
a righteous journalist
是个正义感很强的记者
who always reported crimes committed by politicians, right?
常举发政治家的不法行为  对吧
After you father passed away,
你在令尊死后
you started working in Tokiwa Corporation
就到常盘集团上班
as the secretary of the president.
担任董事长秘书一职
However, during the process of building the twin towers,
但这次双塔大楼建设的过程中
you saw illegal deals taking place.
又发生了不法的行为
After Mio and Mr. Hara made a discussion,
美绪与原先生商量了之后
they decided to bribe Mr. Oki, the councilman
决定贿赂市议员的大木先生
and ask him to amend the municipal law.
拜托他修订市政法案
As a result, just like your father before you,
而这时继承父亲性格的你
you couldn't tolerate such things.
无法容忍发生这种事
Thus, you killed the three of them.
所以你就将他们三人都杀了
I didn't...
我没有…
But, Mr. Mouri,
可是  毛利先生
the sake cups which the murderer left at the crime scene
凶手留在犯案现场的小酒杯
has nothing to do with Miss Sawaguchi.
和泽口小姐并没有任何关系啊
No, Inspector Megure,
不  目暮警部
The Kanji for sake cup is boar and kuchi.
小酒杯的汉字写法就是"猪口"
Miss Sawaguchi was born in the year of the boar.
泽口小姐的生肖属猪
Plus, her name contains the character kuchi.
而且她的姓里有一个"口"字
Combining the two parts and you get "sake cup".
两者合起来就变成"猪口"
Which means,
也就是说她把
she used sake cups to reveal her identity
如同自己的替身的小酒杯敲碎
and smashed the cups
把继承自父亲的那种
to represent the anger that's killing her
如撕裂身体般的愤怒
and send a message at the crime scene.
化作讯息留在现场
That explains the matter!
原来如此
Though he's not asleep,
虽然没睡着
his deduction sounds quite logical.
不过推论倒是很合乎逻辑
That's just a bunch of crap you made up.
那只是你牵强附会随便胡扯出来的吧
What the hell did you say?
你说什么
That's because the sake cup wasn't broken this time.
因为这次小酒杯并没有碎裂啊
If she really wants to show that
如果她真的想表现出
she was so angry that she wanted to break her body...
如身体撕裂般的愤怒的话…
Shut up, you brat!
吵死人了  你这家伙
That hurts!
好痛
You seem to be having a hard time.
好像很辛苦哦
If you're aware, why don't you give me some advice?
知道的话就快帮忙给点意见嘛
Well...
这个嘛…
The only thing I can say is that,
我能说的顶多是
Mio seemed to have drunken a lot of alcohol.
美绪小姐应该喝了很多酒吧
If she wasn't so drunk,
如果她没醉的话
she would have at least felt something
当钩子钩到她项链上的时候
when something was hooked up to her neckless, right?
她会没有感觉吗
The pearl.
珍珠
Why would it be here?
为什么会掉在这里
Wait, does this mean...
等一下  难道说…
Mr. Kazama,
风间先生
I didn't do anything, you know it, right?
我什么都没有做  对吧
I have no idea. It was too dark.
我不知道  因为很暗
So I didn't know what have happened...
所以发生什么事我也…
If that guy is the murderer...
如果那个人是凶手的话…
I see. So that's his motive!
原来如此  原来这就是动机
But if so,
可是如果是这样的话
what about... what about that case...
那么  那个事件…
I see.
原来如此
It explains everything.
原来是那个意思啊
Now I see
这下我完全了解了
the whole picture of the three mysterious murders.
这三个奇妙的事件的全貌
(Basement Level 4 Power Room)
[地下4楼 电力室]
What was that?
怎么了
Why is the building shaking!
大楼怎么在摇动
Is it an earthquake?
是地震吗
What on earth has happened?
到底发生什么事了
There was an explosion?
发生爆炸
Where?
在哪里
In the power room and the power generator room at the 4th basement level!
地下4楼的电机室和发电机室
And the computer room on the 40th floor.
还有40楼的电脑室
The computer room...
电脑室…
Mr. Kazama,
风间先生
the main computer of Tokiwa Corporation is there.
那里有常盘集团的主电脑
All the important files will be gone!
重要的资料全都会不见的
There's a fire on the 40th floor.
40楼的大楼内侧也发生了火灾
Please evacuate everyone immediately!
请尽快离开那里去避难
I understand!
我知道了
Inspector Megure, we must evacuate immediately!
目暮警部  还是赶快撤离比较好
If the power room and the power generator room were both destroyed,
电机室和发电机室都被炸毁
that means the backup generator is also gone.
也就是说连备用电源也没有了
So we can't use the elevators?
那么电梯也不行了吗
Yes.
是的
No, the VIP elevator may still work.
不  观光电梯说不定还会动
Really?
真的吗
It was designed for the VIP guests to escape.
为了提供贵宾逃难时使用
So it runs on an independent power source.
所以电源是另外设置的
It's working...
动了…
What about the maximum load?
搭载人数呢
It could carry 9 adults.
可载9个大人
It'll take too long for everyone to escape by the elevator.
要载完所有的人太花时间了
Is there another way to escape?
有其他的避难方法吗
The emergency stairs will reach the sky bridge at the 60th floor.
走逃生梯到60楼的话
From there, we can descend Tower B to the ground.
可经由连络桥到隔壁的B栋去
All right, all elders, women and children
好  让老人和女性还有小孩们
take the elevator.
搭观光电梯下去
The others take the emergency stairs.
其他的人走逃生梯撤离
What's the situation?
状况如何
The power generator room was destroyed.
发电机室爆炸
The sprinklers are not working.
自动喷淋灭火也无效
What about the fire door?
防火门呢
It was closed.
也是关着的
What about the Sky Bridge which connects the two towers?
从隔壁的B栋到连络桥呢
There's an express elevator that connects to it.
有直达的电梯
All right, Team A, Team B,
好  A小队和B小队
go to the power room and power generator room!
到电机室和发电机室
I'll lead Team C to the Sky Bridge from Tower B
C小队和我从隔壁的大楼
and then walk to the 40th floor.
走连络桥到40楼去
Yes.
是
Get in there, Conan.
进去吧  柯南
Sister Ran, you should go in first.
小兰姐你先进去吧
Just go.
别说那么多了
It's overloaded.
超重了
Conan...
柯南…
It's fine, I'll take the next ride.
没关系  我搭下一班
Please go down.
那请下去吧
The remaining women, Conan,
那么剩下的女士们和柯南
and Mr. Kisaragi,
还有如月先生
are to take the next elevator.
请搭下一班电梯下去吧
I'll take the stairs.
我走楼梯下去
But, Mr. Kisaragi...
可是  如月先生你…
Don't treat me like an elder!
别把我当成老人
Okay... I see.
好…我知道了
Mr. Kazama, please lead the way.
那么风间先生  拜托你了
Okay, everyone,
那么各位
I'll be your guide. Please follow me!
由我带路  请跟我来
Shiratori, you should go with him.
白鸟  你们也先走吧
I'll catch up with you.
我等一下就跟上去
Okay.
好
Professor.
博士
Okay, leave it to me.
好  我知道
Huh?
奇怪
Sorry.
对不起
Please go ahead.
请
But...
可是…
It's fine.
没关系  没关系
We'll go to Tower B
我们从60楼的连络桥
through the Sky Bridge on the 60th floor.
到隔壁的大楼避难就好了
See you down there.
那下面见了
Come on, hurry up.
快  快点  快点
Thank you, kids.
谢谢你们  小朋友
This is terrible. Why is it so dark here?
真讨厌  怎么这么黑
I don't even know where we are.
哪里是哪里都搞不清楚了
What should we do?
怎么办
I gave up my watch flashlight just now.
我刚才把照明手表寄放掉了
This is bad.
这下可惨了
Seriously guys.
真是的
You all should've considered that before exiting.
这种事情在出来之前就要先想到嘛
That's right. Conan and Haibara didn't participate in the game.
对喔  柯南跟灰原没有参加游戏喔
Let's go then!
那快走吧
Wait.
等一下嘛
Why don't we wait for the next elevator?
等下一班电梯不是比较好吗
You're so stupid.
你很笨耶
The next one would surely be full.
下一班电梯一定又是满员了
Anyway, let's get to the 60th floor first.
总之  快到60楼去吧
(Tower B, 45th floor, the elevator lobby)
[B栋45楼 电梯大厅]
Let's get in there!
要进去了喔
Judging from the size of the explosion
这次爆炸的规模
and the concise planning...
以及其周密的计划性…
Is it possible that the people responsible
难不成安装炸弹的是
were from the Black Organization?
那些黑衣的家伙吗
If so,
如果是这样的话
I think I know why
就大概可以推测到
the computer room was blown up.
电脑室被炸掉的理由了
But, why the power room...
可是  为什么连电机室都…
Please get in.
快进去吧
Miss. Chinami, please get in too.
知奈美小姐也一起
We'll need you for questioning later.
具体情况等一下再说吧
I understand.
我知道了
Did they do it to prevent the automatic sprinklers from working?
是为了不让自动喷淋装置运作吗
Or maybe there's another reason?
还是说有其他的目的
Luckily this elevator runs on an independent power supply.
幸好这部电梯用的是不同电源
Otherwise we'll be so exhausted
要不然走楼梯下去的话
walking down the stairs.
可会累惨了
Could it be...
难道…
Gin!
琴酒
Rest in peace, Sherry.
安息吧  雪莉
Eternal peace.
永远地安息吧
Sister Sonoko, your underpants is showing!
园子姐的内裤露出来了
What happened? What happened?
怎么了  怎么了
Why did it stop?
怎么停住了
Is it... not her?
难道…不是她
The red dot disappeared.
激光瞄准点消失了
Did he find out that he got the wrong person?
难道他发现认错人了吗
No, it stopped working!
不行  不能动了
Sister Ran, raise me up!
小兰姐  背我一下
Okay...
好…
Conan, leave it to me!
柯南  交给我吧
You can do it, Sister Ran!
加油  小兰姐
Please!
拜托了
You are awesome, Ran...
好厉害喔  小兰…
(Tower A 45th floor regular elevator lobby)
[A栋45楼 普通电梯大厅]
What floor is this?
这里是几楼
The 45th.
45楼
This is the floor connected to the Sky Bridge.
这是有连络桥的那一层
Oh no, there's so much smoke!
不好了  好多烟呀
Run to the bridge, we can get to the adjoining building!
快过桥逃到隔壁的大楼去吧
It's me. How's everything going with your side?
是我  你那边怎么样
She's not here... I've only seen men.
没有…过来的都只有男的
Maybe she found out that we were looking for her.
大概是发现我们在找她
So she's still up there.
所以还留在上面
I won't let you run away.
但我绝不会让你逃走
Blow up the bridges.
把桥炸掉
As long as we cross over the bridge,
只要过了这座桥
we can get to Tower B!
就到隔壁的大楼了喔
It's the Sky Bridge!
是连络桥
Watch out, Conan!
危险  柯南
What's happened?
怎么回事
The Sky Bridge collapsed!
连络桥塌了
Mr. Mouri, the VIP elevator has stopped.
毛利先生  观光电梯停住了
What?
什么
Ran...
小兰…
Ran, are you all right?!
小兰  你没事吗
I'm fine!
我没事
What should we do, Conan?
怎么办  柯南
This is terrible, there's no way back.
惨了  连退路也被断了
There's smoke coming out from behind the fire door.
防火门的里面有好多烟
How could this be...
怎么会这样…
What do we do?
怎么办
The battery is dead.
电池没电了
It'll be dangerous for us to run around.
乱跑的话反而更危险
Let's wait for help.
在这等人来救我们吧
Are you all right, Conan?
你没事吧  柯南
Sister Ran, are you...
小兰姐  难道你要…
I don't know if this will work
我不知道是不是
like in the movies...
能像电影里一样那么顺利…
Hold tight, Conan.
紧紧地抓好喔  柯南
It's Ran!
是小兰
What? Give me that!
什么  拿来
What are they trying to do?
他们到底想要做什么
Sister Ran, aren't you scared?
小兰姐你不害怕吗
Of course I'm scared...
我当然怕…
But, you are with me now and
可是现在有柯南和我在一起
Shinichi told me to wait for him.
而且新一也说要我等他
I can't die before Shinichi comes back...
我一定要活下去等新一回来…
Conan, I...
柯南  我…
It's going to be all right, Sister Ran.
一定没问题的  小兰姐
I understand your feelings.
我非常了解你的心情
No, the hose is on fire!
不好了  管子着火了
Are you OK, Conan?
没事吧  柯南
You did great, Sister Ran.
你太厉害了  小兰姐
Mr. Mouri...
毛利先生…
Ran!
小兰
I'm so glad that you are fine!
太好了  你没事
Come on, you were so reckless.
真是的  真是太乱来了你…
Run!
危险
Look, the VIP elevator.
你们看  观光电梯
Professor! Where's that person?
博士  那个人在哪
Sorry, I lost him...
不好意思  中途跟丢了…
Also, I haven't seen the kids.
还有  也没看到孩子们
What?
什么
Ayumi, Genta, Mitsuhiko!
步美  元太  光彦
Can you hear me?
听得到吗
Yes, Conan!
听到了  柯南
Where are you guys?
你们现在在哪里
We are... in front of the Sky Bridge on the 60th floor.
我们在…60楼连络桥的前面
What?
什么
They are there?
在那个地方吗
Takagi,
高木
call the rescue helicopter!
快叫救援直升机
Yes...
是…
(Tower B 60th floor elevator lobby)
[B栋60楼 电梯大厅]
Mister, please lend me your flashlight!
叔叔  手电筒借我一下
Boy, come back!
小朋友  回来
What's that?
什么东西
That sound...
那声音是…
It's the skateboard!
是滑板
Is that Conan?
是柯南吗
It hurts!
好痛
That was amazing!
你好厉害喔
You are so cool!
好帅喔
You are a lifesaver!
简直是救世主
Come on.
真是的
Now's not the time for admiration.
现在不是佩服我的时候吧
What the?
什么
It's Conan's skateboard.
是柯南的滑板
Conan just crossed the Sky Bridge on the 60th floor.
刚才柯南飞越了60楼的连络桥
What?
什么
I'm Megure.
我是目暮
Inspector.
警部先生
We are going up now.
大家现在要到上面去了
Please ask the helicopter to land at the roof.
请让直升机停在顶楼
Where are you guys now?
大家  你们现在在哪里
Climbing 15 floors is so tiring.
爬15层楼真的好累喔
Come on, Genta, we are almost there!
元太加油  再一下就到了
You guys go up first.
你们先上去
Conan, where are you going?
柯南你要去哪里
Where are you going?
你要去哪里啊
What is he planning to do?
他要干嘛
I think
柯南他会这么做
Conan must have his reason.
一定有他的想法
Let's get to the roof first.
我们先到屋顶上去吧
Let me think for a moment.
让我想一下嘛
(Tower A 75th floor Banquet Hall)
[A栋75楼 宴会会场]
Someone's there.
有人在那里
It's the one who killed Mr. Oki
是杀死大木先生
and Miss. Mio.
跟美绪小姐的凶手
You wanted to kill Miss. Mio for some reason,
因某个动机而决定杀死美绪小姐
so you presented her that pearl necklace
所以送她那条珍珠项链
and told her to wear it
并叫她戴上那条项链
when she introduced the painting you donated
在开幕典礼致词时
on the opening party.
介绍他送的画
Then the murderer is...
那么凶手就是…
That's right.
没错
Miss. Mio's Japanese painting teacher,
美绪小姐的日本画老师
Mr. Kisaragi.
如月峰水先生
You are...
你就是…
My name is Conan Edogawa.
我叫江户川柯南
I'm a detective.
我是侦探
The pearl necklace
如月先生送给美绪小姐的礼物
which you presented to Miss. Mio.
珍珠项链
You made it easy to be removed, right?
故意弄得很容易散掉  对吧
Then you
然后如月先生
prepared an identical necklace.
又准备了另一条项链
At the party,
在宴会上
you took the second necklace out
你把那条项链拿出来
and hooked it up to
钩住了从富士山的吊轴
the piano wire which hung down along the fold on the curtain
顺着布幕的折痕垂下来的
from the Mount Fuji painting.
带有钩子的钢琴线
After that, you used the lights as a guide
然后再以脚边的灯为记号
and took off Miss. Mio's necklace.
朝美绪走过去把项链弄掉
After that, you said to the panicking Miss. Mio,
然后你再对慌张的美绪小姐说
"It's fine. I'll get it for you."
"没关系  我来帮你戴上"
Then you put on the other necklace on her neck.
把另一条项链戴在她脖子上
The one hooked up to the piano wire.
那条连着钢琴线的项链
Which means...
也就是说…
Miss. Mio's necklace
美绪小姐
didn't get caught in the hook.
并不是项链被钩子钩到
Instead, the hook was already
而是从一开始
attached onto the necklace.
就戴上有钩子的项链
That's why she didn't feel anything.
所以她才没有发现
The pearl I picked up
我捡到的这颗珍珠
is from the necklace
是从被如月先生弄散的
which was removed by Mr. Kisaragi.
原来的那条项链上掉下来的
The sake cup on the stage
舞台上的小酒杯
was put there because
则是为了将此事伪装成
you wanted to make it look like another murder committed by the serial killer.
连续杀人事件而故意放置的
Wait,
等一下
when Mr. Hara was killed,
可是原先生被杀时
Mr. Kisaragi had an alibi.
如月先生有不在场证明啊
That's not strange.
有也不奇怪啊
That's because the one who killed Mr. Hara is someone else.
因为杀原先生的凶手另有其人
The fire has reached the 70th floor!
火窜到70楼了
Where is the helicopter?
救援直升机还没到吗
I'll check on that.
我马上确认
Conan...
柯南…
That night, after we left,
那晚我们回去之后
Mr. Kisaragi went to Mr. Hara's apartment
如月先生为了杀原先生
to kill the latter.
而来到了公寓
However,
可是
Mr. Hara was already shot in the chest and died.
原先生已经被枪击中胸口而死了
Therefore, you decided then to make it seem like
于是你突然想到可以利用这件事
a case of serial homicides.
伪装成连续杀人事件
What's more, this could also be your alibi.
并利用它做为你的不在场证明
If it's a serial homicide,
若是连续杀人事件的话
as long as you have an alibi for one of the murders,
只要其中一件有不在场证明
you wouldn't be suspected for the rest.
就不会被怀疑是凶手
So you copied the scene of Mr. Oki's murder
所以你便模仿大木先生被杀现场
by smashing the sake up you brought there.
把带来的小酒杯弄碎
At that time, pieces of the sake cup
当时碎片的一部份
landed on the dried blood.
飞到已凝固的血上面
That was why none of the pieces in the police's evidence bag
所以警察证物袋里的碎片
had blood on them.
才都没有沾到血
Also, when I saw the picture of
然后那时我看到大木先生
Mr. Oki death in the hotel,
在旅馆被杀时现场的照片
I noticed that the blood splatter was only on the lower part of the closet.
血只有溅到衣橱下面
I think that's because
我想那可能是因为
the painting which you drew was hung there.
那里挂着你所画的画吧
You visited Mr. Oki
你以要送他画为借口
with the excuse that you wanted to give him your paintings
去拜访大木先生
to let his guard down.
让他失去防备心
That was some impressive reasoning, little detective.
真是相当有趣的推理  小侦探
However, your reasoning lack...
可是你的推理…
Of course I have proof.
当然有证据
It's inside your walking stick.
就在那根拐杖里面
The pearl necklace which Miss. Mio originally wore
美绪小姐一开始戴的珍珠项链
should be hidden in there.
应该就藏在里面
How did you know that?
为什么你知道我把它藏在这里
The sound.
声音啊
After Miss. Mio died,
美绪小姐死亡的前后
your walking stick started to
你所撑的拐杖
make different sound.
发出的声音有点不同
Those are the ears of a detective.
不愧是侦探的耳朵
It's here.
来了
But what is the motive?
可是动机到底是什么
Is it because she sold his paintings at a high price
是因为她买了你的画之后
after she bought them?
再高价卖出的关系吗
No, I think the motive should be
不  我想动机可能是因为
this twin towers.
这栋双塔摩天大楼
His motive to kill Mr. Oki and Mr. Hara
杀害大木先生和企图杀害原先生的
should be the same.
理由大概也相同
During the presentation,
你所画的那些富士山的画
I noticed that the Mount Fuji paintings which you drew
在中途突然每张都变成
all had the same angle and composition.
一样的角度和构图
That's because
那是因为
you drew them at the same place.
在同一个地方画的关系吧
I found a hill
那是我在西多摩市的尽头
at the edge of Nishitamashi.
发现的某一个小山丘上
Over the past decades,
我几十年来
I've been painting on that hill.
一直往来于那山丘上作画
However, because I'm getting older and older,
可是因为年纪大了
it became harder and harder for me to climb that hill.
要爬那座山越来越吃力
Therefore, three years ago,
因此就在3年前
I bought that hill and built a house on it
我为了要在有生之年
in order to continue to draw Mount Fuji
继续画富士山
for the rest of my life.
便买下了那个山丘  建了房子
I also built a workshop
并且在视野最好的地方
which had the best view of Mount Fuji.
建了我的工作室
From that window,
从那扇窗子
I could see the whole Mount Fuji.
可以一眼看到富士山全貌
But that woman
可是那个女人
did that!
却做了这种事
So the broken sake cup
难道说被打碎的酒杯
symbolizes Mount Fuji...
指的是富士山…
That's right. Because the twin towers
对  因为双塔摩天大楼
divided Mount Fuji into two parts.
而把富士山分成两半
That's his message of anger.
这是他的愤怒讯息
But when Miss. Mio was killed,
可是美绪小姐被杀害时
the sake cup wasn't broken.
小酒杯并没有打碎啊
That cup was left at the crime scene
那只是为了伪装成
in order to make the murder look like part of a serial homicide.
连续杀人事件才留下的
There was also no need to
而现在已经没有必要
leave the message.
留下讯息了
Since the painting of Mount Fuji
富士山的画已经因
was already cut in half by Miss. Mio's corpse.
美绪小姐的尸体而变成两半了
Since you already found the necklace,
既然都被你发现项链的证据
there is no way for me to defend myself anymore.
那我也已经无法再狡辩了
Sorry.
不好意思
But as a detective, I can't let you die like this.
作为侦探的我  不能让你就这么死掉
We are here!
我们在这里啊
How did you know
你还真想得到啊
Hosui Kisaragi's motive?
如月峰水的杀人动机
On the way to his house,
从我们去他家时
I already noticed something strange.
我就一直觉得不解
When we arrived at Asahino station,
当我们到达朝日野车站时
behind Mitsuhiko was the view of Mount Fuji
光彦身后可看到因双塔摩天大楼
which was divided into two parts by the twin towers.
而被分成两半的富士山
And directly opposite Mount Fuji was
而在其正对面
Mr. Kisaragi's house.
就是如月先生的家
However, the curtains at the
可是他工作室最大的窗子
largest windows in his workshop were closed.
窗帘却是关着的
Perhaps it's because he doesn't want others to see
大概是因为不希望被人看到
Mount Fuji which was divided into two parts by the twin towers.
被双塔摩天大楼分裂的富士山吧
But there's one more thing...
不过  还有一件事…
You want to know who killed Mr. Hara, right?
你想问杀害原先生的凶手  对吧
This is just my assumption.
这只是我的推测
He had a silver knife in his hand at that time.
当时他手上握的是银制小刀
And the word 'silver' is spelled as G I N.
而"银"字用罗马拼音写的话是
You see,
你看
if you think of it as the name of an alcohol,
当把GIN变成酒名的时候
the pronunciation will be different.
念法就改变了不是吗
Gin...
琴酒…
It's likely that when Gin pointed the gun at Mr. Hara,
恐怕原先生当时被琴酒用枪指着
the latter must have picked up the knife on the table.
于是便拿起桌上的小刀
Maybe Gin assumed that
琴酒大概也以为
Mr. Hara wanted to fight him with the knife.
对方是想用小刀对抗手枪
thus he didn't notice that it was actually a message which Mr. Hara left.
而没发现那是他留下的讯息
Mr. Hara used to work with them then?
原先生和他们是一伙的
Yeah, perhaps Mr. Hara hacked into
对啊  可能原先生曾入侵
their computers and stole some confidential files.
他们的电脑并窃取秘密资料吧
That's probably why they killed Mr. Hara
所以他们把原先生除掉
and wiped out all the data in his computer.
消去电脑的资料
Finally, they blew up the main computer
最后再炸掉有可能被用来
which might be used for transferring files in Tokiwa Corporation.
传送资料的常盘集团主电脑
So that's what have happened...
原来是这么一回事啊…
Crap, the battery is dead.
糟糕  电池没电了
I'll go up to find someone to help
我去上面找人帮忙
carry Mr. Kisaragi.
搬运如月先生
Wait for me here.
你在这里等我
(Tower B Rooftop Swimming Pool)
[B栋顶楼 游泳池]
Finally, we are saved!
太好了  得救了
There's no wind now. They should be fine.
现在没什么风  应该没事了吧
Everyone, come back!
大家快回来
Hurry up!
快点
Who... who did this?
是…是谁干的
The helicopter
短时间之内
won't be able to land anytime soon.
直升机大概也无法靠近了
They can only wait for the fire to die out.
他们只能乖乖地等火熄灭
But before that...
但在那之前…
Time up.
TIME UP
What is wrong with this building?
这栋大楼到底怎么回事
Looks like we have to wait for the fire on the roof to go out.
看来只能等顶楼的火灭再说了
We don't have that much time.
我们好像没有那么多时间了
Bomb?!
炸弹
Every table has one.
每张桌子都有
...and the timer.
定时器
We only have four minutes left!
只剩下四分钟了
Shoot, the whole banquet hall will blow up!
可恶  最后再引爆宴会会场
So that no one would know
好让人搞不清楚
who their target is...
他们的目标到底是谁…
Ran...
小兰…
Hurry up!
快点
Sir, the water won't reach!
队长  够不到啊
Damn it, will it not work?
可恶  不行吗
Wait.
等一下
The roof over there.
那边的屋顶
Great, the key's still here.
太好了  钥匙还插在上面
Perfect, we can fly to the adjoining building
对喔  原来可以坐这辆车
in this car.
飞到隔壁的大楼啊
That's impossible.
不可能的
The distance between the two buildings is 50 meters.
大楼之间距离相差50米
If we want to fly over there,
如果要飞过去的话
the flying distance should be 60 meters...
距离大概有60米…
The height difference between the two buildings is 20 meters.
与隔壁大楼的高低差约20米
Objects on earth could
地球上的物体虽然在
move in a constant speed horizontally,
水平方向能以等速前进
but they'll fall at an accelerating rate
可是下坠时会因重力
due to gravity.
而以等比例加速下落
When we fall from 20 meters,
由20米处落下的
the formula to calculate time is
时间计算公式为
t=√2s/g
t等于g分之2s的平方根
t stands for time,
t是所求的时间
g stands for the acceleration of gravity,
g是重力加速度
which is 9.80665 m/s^2,
9.80665米每秒平方
s stands for the distance to fall, which is 20 meters.
s是落下距离的20米
After we plug those numbers into the formula,
把这些数字代入公式
we can get the result.
得到的结果是
2.02 seconds.
2.02秒
This means
也就是说
it'll only take 2 seconds for us to fall from 20 meters.
从20米高处下坠只需两秒
If you want to make 60 meters in 2 seconds...
若要在两秒内前进60米的话…
You would need to move 30 meters in 1 second.
等于1秒要跑30米
Which means the speed required is
换算成时速的话
108 kilometers per hour.
就是时速108公里
Judging from the size of the hall,
但以这会场的大小来看
the car could at most reach a speed of 50 to 60 kilometers per hour.
能够发动的速度最多只有50至60公里
If we drive out the window at that speed,
以这样的速度冲过去
we'll plummet down before we reach the other side.
在到达对面大楼前就会掉下去了
What if I do this?
如果这样的话怎么样
You... you
难…难道
want to use the blast...
你想要跟爆风一起冲出去…
What?
什么
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
Conan wants to fly to the other building
柯南的意思是想要利用
with the help of the blast of the explosion.
爆炸所产生的爆风一起飞过去
What?!
什么
We are going to die anyway if we wait here.
反正等下去也只是死而已
Let's give it a try.
干吧
All right, Conan!
就这么做吧  柯南
Let's do this!
做吧
Let's go out with a bang!
轰轰烈烈地做吧
Whether we'll succeed depends upon the timing.
成功与否的关键就是时机
If the bombs don't explode
如果车子加速
when the car
并冲破窗子的一瞬间
goes through the windows,
炸弹没爆炸的话
we'll decelerate and fall.
就会失速掉下去了
The problem is that we can't see the timer when we are on the car.
问题是坐在车上就看不到定时器了
And my watch is dead.
而我的手表刚好又没电
If that's the case,
这样的话
Ayumi should count the seconds.
就请步美来读秒吧
Ayumi should be able to
如果是步美的话
count exactly 30 seconds!
也许可以准确地猜到30秒
But didn't she just fail?
可是刚刚不就失败了吗
What do you say, Ayumi? Can you do it?
怎么样  步美  你行吗
Though I'm not confident...
虽然没什么信心
But,
可是
as long as I'm with Conan...
只要跟柯南在一起的话…
As long as Conan stays by my side,
只要柯南在我身边的话
I think I can do it!
我想我应该做得到
Ayumi...
步美…
I'll stay beside the timer
那么我先在定时炸弹旁
until there's 30 seconds left.
倒数到30秒之后
After that I'll get in the car. What do you think?
再坐进车子里  怎么样
There's no time for second thoughts.
没时间考虑了
Let's do it that way.
就这么办吧
What? There are bombs in the hall?
什么  会场被装了炸弹
Open the roof of the dome immediately.
马上打开顶楼的圆顶
The roof...
顶楼的…
Come on, hurry up!
别管了  快一点
Mr. Kazama!
风间先生
It's me.
是我
Immediately open the roof of the dome!
马上把屋顶的圆顶打开
Do it now!
马上去做
I'm sorry.
不好意思
What are you going to do, Conan?
你要怎么做呢  柯南
Sister Ran,
小兰姐
I'll go to you now.
我现在就到你那边去
Conan...
柯南…
28...
28…
Hibara!
灰原
What happened?
怎么了
Hibara... she's still counting!
灰原她…她还一直在倒数
What?
什么
Hibara, what are you doing? Come over here!
灰原你在干嘛  快点过来啊
You fool. Isn't this more accurate?
笨蛋  这样数才会准不是吗
Does she plan to
难不成那家伙
stay here and sacrifice herself?
想要自己留下来牺牲吗
What are you doing?!
你要干嘛
My mom said that
我妈有说过
if you leave even a grain of rice in the bowl,
如果留下任何一颗米粒
you would be punished by god.
就会被老天爷惩罚的
We are going now!
要冲了喔
Haibara!
灰原
I won't let go! I won't...
我不会放手的  绝对…
Shoot, the trajectory...
糟糕  这样下去
Haibara will hit the pillar.
灰原会撞到柱子
Let me borrow this!
借我一下
Conan!
柯南
Sister Ran!
小兰姐
We are fine!
没事耶
This is great!
太好了
By the way, Conan,
对了  柯南
where did you learn how to drive?
你是在哪学会开车的
In Hawaii, at my father's...
在夏威夷我爸爸…
Boss, the people who got out in the car
大哥  坐车逃出来的
were five kids and an old man.
是五个小鬼跟一个老头
I think that woman
我想那个女的
didn't go to the party.
应该没来参加宴会吧
Forget about it.
算了
We already achieved our original purpose.
反正最初的目的也已经达成
Yeah...
是啊…
I can't believe that man betrayed us
可是没想到那男人竟背叛我们
and hacked into the organization's computer.
入侵组织的电脑
We know who did it, boss.
我知道了  老大
The hacker came from the twin towers
是从西多摩市的
in Nishitamashi.
双塔摩天大楼入侵的
I knew it was that guy.
果然是原那家伙干的
We already got rid of Hara,
原那家伙已经干掉了
and blew up the main computer of Tokiwa Corporation.
而且常盘集团的主电脑也炸了
The information about our organization wouldn't be leaked.
组织的情报就不会外泄了
I wanted to make that building
本来想把那大楼
the place to execute that woman.
拿来当作那家伙的刑场
I guess I'll save that pleasure
这个乐趣
for another time then.
下次再找机会享受吧
I can't believe Mr. Kisaragi is the murderer.
想不到如月先生竟是凶手
This is so shocking.
很令人吃惊吧
Is it?
是吗
I found him suspicious from the beginning.
我从一开始就觉得他怪怪的
The police's investigation
警方的搜查
will probably stop here.
大概就到这里为止吧
The investigation into Mr. Hara's murder which was committed by Gin
琴酒杀害原先生的事件
will go nowhere.
大概也会不了了之吧
The truth of the explosion
爆炸案的真相
won't be revealed either.
也就这样石沉大海了
Thanks for what you did just now.
刚刚真是谢谢你
Thanks to you that I was saved.
托你的福得救了
It's nothing.
没什么啦
I just fulfilled my duty
我只是尽了
as a man.
身为男人的义务而已
Thank you too, Kojima.
小岛也是
So, I'm like a grain of rice to you, huh?
原来我跟米粒是一样的啊
By the way, Ayumi,
对了  步美
how did you manage to
为什么这次又可以
accurately count down from 30 seconds?
准确地猜出30秒呢
It's just by coincidence.
凑巧的啦
Actually, it's all because of Conan.
其实  都是托柯南的福
When you are around me, I'll become nervous and my heart starts to race.
因为柯南在身边我就紧张得心砰砰乱跳
That's how I count time by counting my heartbeat.
所以我光靠心跳就能知道时间
Come to think of it,
这么说来
the first time you managed to win the 30s game...
一开始猜那30秒时也是…
28, 29, 30!
28  29  30
That's why you said that
所以你才说
as long as I was with you...
只要有我在身边的话…
Mitsuhiko, you were pretty cool!
光彦你也很酷喔
I'm not.
哪里
So are you, Genta!
元太也是
Ha... really?
哈…是吗
What are you going to do?
怎么办
What do you mean...
什么怎么办…
If you break Yoshida's heart,
如果你让吉田伤心的话
I'll never forgive you.
我绝不会原谅你喔
Wait!
等一下
Is this car...
这部车该不会是…
That's right.
对啊
That's your prize.
是大叔的奖品
The Mustang Convertible.
MUSTANG CONVERTIBLE
My dream car...
我梦寐以求的车子…
Wait.
等等喔
Maybe it could still function after it dries...
烘干的话  说不定还能开…